I have to say one of my uh favorite
stories of the last week involved a
young lady who took an early morning
Excursion which entailed a shimming of
sorts to retrieve an unsavory Relic or
in layman's terms when that sister took
that Confederate flag down 30-year-old
Bri new scaled a 30ft pole Saturday and
descended with the flag in hand ladies
and Gentlemen please welcome bad flag
snatcher Bri
Newsome
hey come on thanks so much for being on
the show come on over just have to see
you right there we
go
yes thanks thanks so much for joining us
yeah thanks for having me uh also oh I
noticed when uh you tweeted you were
excited to be in the show uh to share
some mint julips with me so let's let's
have a little
uh joke just kind of little to yes and
discuss the discussion of removing the
flag exactly so so here's what I want to
know how much how much planning like
went into that whole thing I mean did
you have like a a pole in your backyard
did you on well yeah so it was it was
about 10 of us um who who you know
pulled the whole thing together
including um folks who were down in
South Carolina who could like actually
go down there and look at the scene see
what all would be involved what roles
would you know be required um and so
then by the time we came together some
of those Logistics had been laid out and
it was just a matter of you know who's
going to fill what RS including climbing
the pole so I was like yeah I'll do it
and had I climb the pole before no but
let's do it so there's a whole group of
you and you kind of rais your hands like
wait
wait yeah I mean yeah I mean you know we
we went through it and of course we had
to discuss that you know the the two
roles one of climbing the pole and one
of being at the bottom and watching
guard those two people might be arrested
how many people were on the scene during
the uh uh about nine of us about there
were nine people there I didn't know
that okay so there there's a whole group
of you that did this together oh yeah
was coordinated oh that's good did you
guys all work in your core like at the
same time before that's what I'd have to
do like for we here's what I so what
went through your mind the moment like
you had that flag where did you realize
the importance of this or I mean were
you just kind of like oh I can see my
house from here I
mean was it a heady type of thing what
did that feel yeah it was just it was
just like this really amazing feeling of
like mission accomplished you know I
mean um one of the the hardest points or
you know that I was concerned about was
just getting
about like 15t up the pole um and I knew
once I got that far up I was pretty much
clear to make it up there and so then
once I got up there and was able to
unhook the flag high enough so no one
could grab you exactly exactly yeah and
so once I got up there and grabbed it it
was just like yes take me to jail
awesome so
oh and when you were about halfway up
isn't that when the uh Capitol police
showed up yes yeah so what was that were
you scared of that moment or what did
that feel like no not really cuz I was I
was out of reach it was just right it
kind of grab theist
now it was kind of this awkward thing of
them telling me to come down and me just
being like no
right you know were they pretty cool
about it yeah I mean clearly I had
ruined their day I mean that's hilarious
sorry like oop sorry guys sorry for the
inconvenience some people have compared
you to Rosa Parks have called you like a
superhero right okay so here's what I
want to do uh we need to come up with a
proper superhero name for you right okay
so he can vote on this the
Ascender um Soul pole Soul pole that's
kind of cool sounds like Frozone uh oh I
like sister
swifter or uh Queen
Brie which one Queen Bri Queen
Bri actually I think the proper
superhero name is Bri is Bri new there
you go thank you okay oh last thing so
we also we have an award that we want to
give you okay uh it's titled the Bri
Newsome
award I don't know how that worked it
just happened and uh uh unfortunately I
don't have it here but we put it in a
place that might be easy for you to get
so we could just show uh yeah so it's
right there yeah so you can grab it no
no no no no that's not
true no no no the brome award from the
nightly show for C unbelievable what you
did